Hello friends, welcome to Tip Insights.
In today's video, we will talk
about claim intimation. Whenever we get our
treatment done in a non-network hospital,
then we have to inform the insurance company or
TPA within 24 hours, that is,
within 24 hours of our admission, we have to inform the insurance company or TPA. So,
how is the process of intimating it? In today's
video, I am going to tell you in detail.
I was getting a lot of comments on
this topic that sir, we have made a
video on how to do claim intimation. So,
I thought of making a video for everyone so
that
no one faces any problem while doing claim intimation.
Today's video is going to be for all of you. So,
you guys stay tuned till the end. If
you are new to the channel, then subscribe to the channel and
press the bell icon
so that you keep getting notifications of new videos. So,
let's start the video.
[Music]
Whenever we get our treatment done in a non-network
hospital, then within
24 hours of admission, we have to inform the insurance company or TPA.  Internally, we have to
inform the insurance company or TPA
that we are getting
our treatment done in this non-network hospital which
is not in your network list, so please
provide us an intimation number
so that when we claim our bill or
reverse the bill later, that intimation number
reaches you in advance and
we do not face any problem in getting the claim. There are
different types of processes for
giving intimation to the health insurance company or TPA, one is by
talking to the customer care, secondly
you can give intimation to them by visiting the website of the insurance company or TPA,
you can also give intimation by talking to the customer care,
that is the easiest way,
many people do
not get the option of claim intimation by going to the website or not
everyone knows how to fill the form that opens on it,
so I would
suggest you that maximum number of people should
call and talk to the customer care and tell them about their claim intimation
and that is an
intimation.  They will also provide you with an email ID, a
printout of which you must
attach with your claim.
Secondly, they will also provide you with a verbal or written note. The
claim number, which is the intimation
number, must be mentioned on the form as well.
You can write somewhere inside that
this is our claim intimation number. This will ensure you have
no problem in claiming.
Secondly, you need to visit your
insurance company or TPA's website
and a form will open.
Click on "Claim Intimation" and enter
your policy number or
member ID. The entire form will
open.
Fill in the required information.
After that, an intimation number will be generated from there.
You must
keep a printout of this information safely. When your treatment is
complete, you must attach the printout of this intimation along with your bill,
claim forms A and B,
and send it to the insurance company and
TPA.  I want to tell you one more thing,
many people do
not even know that claim intimation is
also given in cashless claim or
in resource claim
because if cashless claim is rejected then
in bill resource claim,
intimation already goes to them which is
sent by the hospital after filling the pre-authorization form, so
after knowing the already intimation in it, you do not need to give separate intimation
but you
can easily reverse the resource, otherwise
you people will have problem with one company,
I will open my website and
show you how the claim intimation
option comes, when we go to the website of Paramount TPA, the
claim intimation number will
open like this, I am going to show you people on the screen, we
will search, first of all
you people have to click on the website which is visible in front of you
and after that we have to go to it,
see in it towards the bottom, this download e-
card option is coming, after this we have to
go down,
see this  The option of claim intimation has
come up here, as soon as we
click on this, see here when
we click on claim intimation,
here we click on the claim intimation which is below,
see in this the type of
policy, all this has opened in front of it, it is
individual policy, this is an
option of individual policy, it is of a group i.e.
corporate policy, you can also enter the group code
here, the employee number which is an employee
number in the corporate policy,
you can also enter that in it,
after this you have to enter the PHS ID as well and
as soon as you submit it, the entire details will
open in a form type and by
filling your details in it you
can give intimation to the insurance company or TPA,
so in today's video I told you people
how you can
get the intimation number of your claim from the insurance company,
either by talking to the customer care
or by going to their website, you people will have to fill that form
and from there you people will get
an intimation number, so
I have told you the entire process in detail  I have explained it to you. If
you liked the video, then
like the video, subscribe to the channel and
press the bell icon
so that you keep getting notifications of new videos. If you have
any questions regarding the video, please
write them in the comment section and
send them. Apart from this, if you have
any query regarding your health insurance claim, then
you can also share your query letter with me.
You will definitely
get the answer to that too. So that's all for today's video. See you
in the next video, till then,
goodbye.